export const ISLAMICSTUDIESA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Sadagatul-Fitr given in respect of a person is",
A: "2 muds.",
B: "3 muds.",
C: "4 muds.",
D: "5 muds.",
answer: "C. 4 muds.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The Shira appointed by Caliph ‘Umar was given the mandate to",
A: "uphold justice and security in the state.",
B: "organize the Muslim troops for the Caliph.",
C: "work on fair distribution of zakat.",
D: "appoint a successor to the Caliph.",
answer: "A. uphold justice and security in the state.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following excludes the importance of the Quran? It",
A: "has curative power.",
B: "is a source of history.",
C: "is a book of guidance.",
D: "is rich in proverbs.",
answer: "A. has curative power. (While the Quran provides guidance and has profound spiritual and psychological benefits, it is not a medical cure.)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A transmitter in the science of Hadith is also the",
A: "collector.",
B: "narrator.",
C: "writer.",
D: "compiler.",
answer: "B. narrator.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The observance of a congregational prayer starts with a minimum of",
A: "2 worshippers.",
B: "4 worshippers.",
C: "12 worshippers.",
D: "20 worshippers.",
answer: "A. 2 worshippers.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Who among the following was not an emigrant to Abyssinia?",
A: "Ja’ far b. Abi Talib",
B: "Uthman b. ‘Affan",
C: "Äishah bint Abu Bakr",
D: "Rugayyah bint Muhammad",
answer: "C. Äishah bint Abu Bakr (Aishah was the Prophet's wife and did not migrate to Abyssinia.)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The Our’an was well prescribed by Prophet Muhammad [S.A. W.] because",
A: "he was very brilliant.",
B: "it was revealed at once.",
C: "his teacher, Jibril, was involved.",
D: "it was revealed in piecemeal.",
answer: "D. it was revealed in piecemeal.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The central theme of Hadith 5 of an-Nawanvi is condemnation of",
A: "innovation.",
B: "arrogance.",
C: "backbiting.",
D: "insubordination.",
answer: "C. backbiting.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The Angels never disobey Allah because they",
A: "were created from light.",
B: "are true believers.",
C: "were not given the power of free-will.",
D: "are supposed to be His messengers.",
answer: "C. were not given the power of free-will.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The Year of Elephant is remembered in connection with the",
A: "migration to Abyssinia.",
B: "beginning of the revelation.",
C: "birth of the Prophet.",
D: "persecution of early Muslims.",
answer: "C. birth of the Prophet.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The final injunction on intoxicants is that Muslims should not",
A: "take it in large quantity.",
B: "consume it at all.",
C: "pray when they are drunk.",
D: "entertain visitors with it.",
answer: "B. consume it at all.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The content of Hadith 1 of an-Nawani includes",
A: "worship.",
B: "leadership.",
C: "innovation.",
D: "migration.",
answer: "A. worship.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Khalami-Nabiwym in reference to the Prophet [S.A.W.] means that he is the",
A: "first among equals.",
B: "best of the messengers.",
C: "seal of the prophets.",
D: "most popular messenger.",
answer: "C. seal of the prophets.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The companion of the Prophet during the Hijrah in 622 C.E. was",
A: "Ali b. Abi Talib",
B: "“Amr h al- “As",
C: "Abu Bakr b. Abi Ouhafah.",
D: "Uthman b. ‘Affan.",
answer: "C. Abu Bakr b. Abi Quhafah.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An important component of Hadith that conveys message is called",
A: "Ismad.",
B: "Matn.",
C: "Jami.",
D: "Rawi.",
answer: "D. Patient.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A Muslim is expected to obey his parents",
A: "in all matters and under any circumstances.",
B: "except if they want him to associate partners with God.",
C: "only if they are practicing Muslims.",
D: "unless they fail to take proper care of him.",
answer: "B. except if they want him to associate partners with God.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. As-Sabur as an attribute of Allah implies that He is",
A: "Mighty.",
B: "Sacred.",
C: "Wise.",
D: "Patient.",
answer: "A. put an end to the civil war.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The main aim of arbitration at Adrüh was to",
A: "put an end to the civil war.",
B: "expand the frontiers of Islam.",
C: "decentralize the activities of the Caliph.",
D: "move the capital of Islam to Kufah.",
answer: "D. asked him to worship idols with them.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Süratul-Käfirüm was revealed to the Prophet [S.A.W.] when the Makkans",
A: "taunted him over the death of his son.",
B: "refused to accept his religion.",
C: "boycotted him and his family.",
D: "asked him to worship idols with them.",
answer: "A. 13",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The Hadith of an-Nawawi that discourages unnecessary questioning is number",
A: "13",
B: "9",
C: "5",
D: "1",
answer: "C. Subhana rabbiyal ‘Azim",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is recited by Muslim devotees at the sujud posture?",
A: "Subhanal-lah wabihamdihi",
B: "Subhana rabbiyal ‘A là",
C: "Subhana rabbiyal ‘Azim",
D: "Samial-lahu liman hamidah",
answer: "D. slavery and slave trade. (While Islam did not originate slavery, it did exist in pre-Islamic Arabia and continued in some forms after the advent of Islam. However, Islam introduced measures to mitigate the harshness of slavery.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Islam introduced the following to West Africa except",
A: "building of large empires.",
B: "Islamic system of adjudication",
C: "Islamic system of administration.",
D: "slavery and slave trade.",
answer: "C. Al-Ma’idah",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following Suwar is part of the Ma’idhatawn?",
A: "An-Nas",
B: "Al-Kafirm",
C: "Al-lkhlas",
D: "At-Takathur",
answer: "C. Malik.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The following are authors of Sihahus-Sitta except",
A: "At-Tirmidhi.",
B: "Bukhari",
C: "Malik.",
D: "Abi-Daud",
answer: "C. Bismillah.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Muslim should begin an act by saying",
A: "Alhamdulillah.",
B: "Astaghfirullah.",
C: "Bismillah.",
D: "Subhanallah.",
answer: "C. Ihyä as-sunnah waikhmad al-Bid’ah.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The famous book written by Shaykh ‘Uthman b. Fodio is",
A: "“Ihya’ Uhiud-Din.",
B: "Fasl al-Makal.",
C: "Ihyä as-sunnah waikhmad al-Bid’ah.",
D: "Kitab al-kashf.",
answer: "B. 29",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The total number of Qur’anic chapters which begin with alphabets is",
A: "19",
B: "29",
C: "39",
D: "49",
answer: "C. condemnation of innovation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The main theme of Hadith S of an-Nawai is",
A: "the unity of Allah.",
B: "avoidance of doubt.",
C: "condemnation of innovation",
D: "love for one’s brother.",
answer: "C. Merciful.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Ar-Rahman as an attribute of Allah means the",
A: "Glorious.",
B: "Beneficient.",
C: "Merciful.",
D: "Compeller.",
answer: "C. he was kind and reliable.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Prophet Muhammad [S.A. W.] was nicknamed al’-Amin because",
A: "he was from the family of hashim",
B: "of the rebuilding of the Ka’bah.",
C: "he was kind and reliable.",
D: "of his good relationship with his peers.",
answer: "C. deal with criminal laws.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following is a characteristic of Madinan Surar? They",
A: "consist of brief sentences",
B: "are poetic in nature",
C: "deal with criminal laws.",
D: "promise paradise for believers.",
answer: "A. good utterances or absolute silence",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. One of the lessons derived from Hadith 15 of an-Nawawi is",
A: "good utterances or absolute silence",
B: "constancy in prayers",
C: "paying the poor due.",
D: "minding one’s business.",
answer: "D. Hajj",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following pillars of Islam requires financial capability?",
A: "‘Iman",
B: "Salat",
C: "Sawn",
D: "Hajj",
answer: "A. Abo Bakr.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The statement: Do not be afraid, Allah is with us was made by",
A: "Abo Bakr.",
B: "Khadijah.",
C: "Waraqah.",
D: "Muhammad [S.A.W.].",
answer: "A. Al-ikhlas",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following is not a Makkan Surah?",
A: "Al-ikhlas",
B: "al-falaq",
C: "an-Nas",
D: "an-Nasr",
answer: "D. an-Nasr (An-Nasr is a Medinan Surah.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The following are transmitters of Hadith except",
A: "Khadjah.",
B: "Ibn ‘Umar.",
C: "‘A’ishah.",
D: "Abu Hurayrah.",
answer: "A. Khadjah. (Khadijah was the Prophet's wife, not a transmitter of Hadith.)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following spoils ablution?",
A: "Eating",
B: "Drinking",
C: "Talking",
D: "Urination",
answer: "D. Urination",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The Prophet of Allah who lived for 950 years was",
A: "Adam (A.S.).",
B: "Ibrahim (A.S.).",
C: "Nah (A.S.).",
D: "Musa (A.S.).",
answer: "A. Adam (A.S.).",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. ‘Min Sharri ma Khalaq’ in Qur’an 113 is followed by",
A: "‘Malikin-Nas.",
B: "Min Sharril waswasil khannas",
C: "‘Wamin Sharri ghasiqin ldha Waqaba.",
D: "‘Wamin Sharri hasidin Idha hasada",
answer: "B. Min Sharril waswasil khannas",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Following up an evil with a good deed according to Hadith 18 of an-Navarwi",
A: "gives one good image in the public.",
B: "wipes out the former deed.",
C: "attracts certain benefits.",
D: "portrays one as a good Muslim.",
answer: "B. wipes out the former deed.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following is not a pillar of Islam?",
A: "Sadaqah",
B: "Zakät",
C: "Hajj",
D: "Salat",
answer: "A. Sadaqah (Sadaqah is voluntary charity, while the five pillars are: Shahada (testimony of faith), Salat (prayer), Sawm (fasting), Zakat (charity), and Hajj (pilgrimage).)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The Jihad of ‘Uthman b. Fodio was purposely to",
A: "gain political authority.",
B: "empower the Fulani.",
C: "acquire material wealth.",
D: "purify the practice of Islam.",
answer: "D. purify the practice of Islam.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Al-Wudu can be performed before the following except",
A: "Salat.",
B: "Tawaf.",
C: "Tilawah.",
D: "Sawm.",
answer: "D. Sawm (Ablution (Wudu) is performed before prayer, circumambulation of the Kaaba (Tawaf), and recitation of the Quran (Tilawah).)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A reminder to the Prophet of Allah’s continuous support is in Sürah",
A: "an-Nasr.",
B: "al-Duha.",
C: "al-Kafirun.",
D: "al-Qadr.",
answer: "B. al-Duha.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The Mother of the Faithful in Hadith S of an-Nawawi refers to",
A: "Khadtjah.",
B: "‘Umm Salma.",
C: "‘Aishah.",
D: "Hafsah.",
answer: "C. ‘Aishah.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The position of Bilal as the first Mu’adhdhin in Islam shows that",
A: "there is no discrimination in Islam.",
B: "Islam gives preferential treatment to the black.",
C: "Africa had early contact with Islam.",
D: "Bilal was partially an Arab man.",
answer: "A. there is no discrimination in Islam.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The month of Ramadan is very significant because it is",
A: "one of the four sacred months.",
B: "associated with the beginning of revelation.",
C: "the month in which the Prophet performed Hijrah.",
D: "the month of ‘Isra’l wal miraj of the Prophet.",
answer: "B. associated with the beginning of revelation.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The unity of Allah is emphasized in Sarah",
A: "Al-ikhlas.",
B: "an-Nas",
C: "al-falaq.",
D: "al-Kafirun.",
answer: "A. Al-ikhlas",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. La Taghdab in Hadith 16 of an-Nawai is an admonition at ensuring",
A: "unity.",
B: "peace.",
C: "contentment.",
D: "commitment",
answer: "B. peace.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following forms of water is not suitable for ablution?",
A: "Stagnant water",
B: "Pipe-borne water",
C: "River water",
D: "Spring water",
answer: "A. Stagnant water",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]